in a document if we suspect we've
misspelled a word we can use the fine
function to highlight the error and
correct it or delete it within our DNA
that function is taken on by a system
called CRISPR casts nine CRISPR is short
for clustered regularly interspaced
short palindromic repeats CRISPR
consists of two components the caste
nine protein that can cut DNA and a
guide RNA that can recognize the
sequence of DNA to be edited to use
CRISPR casts nine scientists first
identify the sequence of the human
genome that's causing a health problem
then they create a specific guide RNA to
recognize that particular stretch of a's
t's g's and c's in the DNA the guide RNA
is attached to the DNA cutting enzyme
cast 9 and then this complex is
introduced to the target cells it
locates the target letter sequence and
cuts the DNA at that point scientists
can then edit the existing genome by
either modifying deleting or inserting
new sequences it effectively makes
CRISPR cast 9 a cut-and-paste tool for
DNA editing in the future scientists
hope to use CRISPR cast 9 to develop
critical advances in patient care or
even cure lifelong inherited diseases